Craig Simpson

Contact

Address

South Woodham Ferrers, Essex, CM3 5WS

Phone

07540696829

E-mail

simpson_cmes@hotmail.co.uk

Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

React

Version Control

Responsive Design

Interests

Computing

Gaming

Playing Football

A self-taught front-end developer currently working through the Full Stack Engineer course on codecademy while pursuing the opportunity to begin a career path in the web development industry. I have a particular interest in front end development and am eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organisational skills, while being motivated to learn, grow and excel in the industry.

I have a scientific background, working in Microbiology for 7 years, progressing from a lab assistant to a fully qualified Biomedical Scientist.

Personal online portfolio: https://cmesimpsonportfolio.netlify.app/

Work History

2016-10 -2021-09

Biomedical Scientist

IPP Pathology First, Basildon, Essex

- Recorded data, analysed test results and kept meticulous reports, using WinPath LIMS system.
- Resolved data and recorded discrepancies with actionable corrective solutions.
- Kiestra Key User Populated databases and managed users for new hardware.
- Assessed hardware failures and performed troubleshooting of analysers.
- Maintained strict adherence to laboratory guidelines and regulations, verifying safety and protective procedures.

2015-09 -2016-10

Associate Practitioner

IPP Pathology First, Basildon, Essex

- Delivered patient results within specific timeframes.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and fast-paced atmosphere.
- Actively listened to customers, handled concerns quickly and escalated major issues to supervisor.
- Participated in continuous improvement by completing HCPC registration portfolio.

2014-08 -2015-09

Medical Laboratory Assistant

Southend University Hospital, NHS, Southend, Essex

- Maintained confidentiality of all patient information to conform with regulatory standards.
- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving issues.

Education

2010-09 -	Bachelor of Science: Biomedical Sciences
2013-09	Anglia Ruskin University - Cambridge
2002-09 -	William De Ferrers School - South Woodham Ferrers, Essex
2009-07	3 GCE 'A' Levels
	10 GCSEs (Grades A - C)